Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
They've got 21 hostages.
Including one child. Lina.
Her father is Colonel Alexis Mayard.
head of the lab.
The mother's in the army.
Looks like they were visiting the dad
at work when the hostage taking began.
The lone terrorist used to work
at the lab. He's an idealist.
He's angry about the weapons they develop
and he wants the whole country to know.
He's unstable and paranoid.
What do they make in the lab?
Don't know. It's classified.
All they told me is it's explosives.
Teams of two. Your usual partners.
Standard rules of engagement.
Reasonable self-defense.
imminent threat to a hostage's life
or a direct order.
We know the facility makes explosives.
So hold your fire.
We'll go in through the service tunnel.
Let's move!
Attention all units.
approaching the target.
All units maintain position.
I demand to speak
to the Defense Minister right now.
And I want to talk to a journalist too.
If you don't make it happen.
I'll kill someone.
David and Laurent
in position. Bravo Charlie.
What's taking so long?
You want me to shoot someone? Is that it?
I'll give you 15 minutes.
After that I kill everyone.
You hear me?
Fifteen minutes!
You're not gonna trick us
into anything else!
Okay.
I have a visual on the hostages.
Nothing to report. No apparent injuries.
Do you understand?
Fuck!
Negotiations interrupted.
Fuck it!
Have a visual on the target.
He has a 12-gauge pump-action shotgun.
There's a detonator in his left hand.
He looks nervous.
I can't take this anymore!
Stop looking at me!
I've lost Oscar 12.
I can't see the little girl.
I don't know where she is.
Target is on the move.
-Shit!
-He just exited the cafeteria.
Heads up.
Oscar 9 is moving towards the back.
I can't see what she's doing.
She just picked up a bag.
What the hell is she doing?
You! Get up!
Just do it! Fuck!
You too!
She's loading a Beretta.
All hell's gonna break loose.
We need to act now.
The door could be rigged.
We go through the back.
You too! Get the fuck up!
Get the fuck up! Now!
Shit!
Police!
-Police!
-Stay with me. Amal. Listen to me. honey.
-Target is neutralized.
-You're gonna be fine. Just stay.
-Sir. we're evacuating. Sir!
-Need to apply pressure. She's been shot.
-Evacuating!
-We'll take care of her.
Keep applying pressure!
Wait. wait! She's been hit!
-Step away!
-She's been hit!
We have a timer.
Three minutes. Get everyone out.
-Back away. sir!
-Ma'am. can you hear me? Can you hear me?
-Keep moving!
-We're extracting!
Can you hear my voice. ma'am?
We're gonna take care of you.
-My daughter.
-Go. go!
-Move!
-Let go. Did you hear what I said?
Go!
-Your daughter? Where's your daughter?
-She's in the lab.
-Come on. we have to go.
-Lab…
-She's in the lab.
-She's in the lab?
-The guy planted explosives!
-We'll handle it. sir.
-My daughter's in the lab!
-Get him out of here.
We'll get her. Medic!
-Doc! Over here!
-I'll find your daughter. ma'am.
I'll find your girl.
I have a daughter too.
Save her.
Everyone out!
Go. go. go. Get out of here!
Everyone evacuate!
No. wait!
Hold up! We gotta find the girl!
We're missing the girl!
You've got 90 seconds.
Then get out.
We had almost no time left.
so Laurent and I
went back to look for the little girl.
Uh… We ran down the halls and. um…
And Lina Mayard died in the explosion
at the lab shortly after that?
Along with Lieutenant Laurent Villiers.
Yeah.
Fifteen years ago to the day.
Can you think of any other details?
Whatever comes to mind
that you could share with us?
No.
Chloé.
let's look at the wife next.
Right. This is Amal Mayard.
After her daughter died.
she quit the force and went off the radar.
A year later. the records show
she was killed
in a car accident in Turkey.
The husband.
on the other hand. switched sides.
He spent ten years in prison
at Bois-D'arcy for arms trafficking.
In explosives mostly.
That's where he crossed paths
with Kröller.
He just got out this November.
and no further sign of him.
Not even digitally.
Through Kröller. he put together
the crew for the CL-20 job.
We assume he was the one
who eliminated Kröller
when we arrested him yesterday.
And he was one of the guys who put
the CL-20 in Chris top he's hospital room.
I've got half of Recon working on it.
ELITE FORCE
Listen. it's a beast. You hear that?
Okay. Come on. Safari Guy. Rev that motor.
-Watch out. guys. It can get pretty noisy.
-You asked for it!
-You ready. Max? Not bad. huh?
-A bit more.
Hang on. hang on. Listen.
-It's too much.
-Again?
-It's vibrating my jaw!
-Turn it off!
No. no. no!
-We can't hear you!
-It's making my teeth hurt.
Turn it off!
Yeah!
-It's his foot. not mine.
-Whoa!
Take your foot off the gas. why don't you?
-I can make some noise of my own!
-Watch out. Max. he means it!
David. wait.
You getting anywhere?
There's progress. There's progress. but…
All I really wanted was to be with him
in the time he had left.
You got to be with him every day.
I won't have that.
Promise me they won't get away.
They won't get away. Don't worry.
I swear to you.
Hey. I've never seen this one.
That was a barbecue at Chris top he's.
But you were there. you know.
Yeah. I remember that day.
-I was 10 years old. yeah.
-Yeah.
You know why you remember it?
No.
You tossed back
a whole glass of wine that afternoon.
Yeah. I remember.
-First time I ever got wasted.
-Your mother. she let us have it.
Oh. we got an earful!
-Oh! You should have heard her.
-Sorry.
I'm sorry about Christophe.
When I was little. Dad would take me
to the Chinese buffet in Versailles.
It was a thing we did. Just the two of us.
Mom couldn't stand that place.
I go eat there every year now
on the day that he died.
Usually on my own. but…
Since it's tonight. I thought
maybe you might wanna come too.
Ah.
No.
No. I can't tonight.
I have to check something.
Okay.
Breathing down our necks all day
isn't gonna make us any faster.
I might have a lead on Mayard. You coming?
CAPTAIN CHLOÉ LEFORT
LIEUTENANT ADRIEN LEDUC
LABORATORY STORAGE UNIT
MINISTRY OF JUSTICE
CRIMINAL RECORD NUMBER 1
FEBRUARY 10. 2011: TRESPASSING
AT A CLASSIFIED DEFENSE FACILITY
David. I told you when I get anything.
you'll be the first to hear it.
I thought something might've come up.
Well. I've got nothing.
so off you go. please.
Can I take a look?
I guess.
FEBRUARY 10TH 2010
EDITED: JUNE 30TH 2016
TODAY. FEBRUARY 10TH. 2 MINUTES AGO
FEBRUARY 10. 2011: TRESPASSING
AT A CLASSIFIED DEFENSE FACILITY
Where you headed?
The firing range. you?
You put your weapons in a gym bag now?
Asshole.
Let me see what you got.
Do you want me to come along?
This isn't something
you wanna be a part of.
You know. with gear like that.
it rarely ends well.
Yeah well.
it doesn't always end well.
VICTOR DUTEL
OFFICER LIEUTENANT
LAURENT VILLIERS: OFFICER LIEUTENANT
Oh. fuck.
I wouldn't have followed you
if you'd just asked me to come.
You think I don't know where you're going?
It's the anniversary of Dad's death.
We're five miles from where it happened.
So. what?
Going to pay your respects?
Is that the idea?
Go home. Max.
You know what?
Maybe I'll do the same thing. Why not?
Don't worry. I won't go with you.
I'll be there. you'll be there.
but not together. No problem.
You're right. That's where I'm going.
But not to pay my respects.
The man who killed Christophe. Mayard…
He believes we're responsible
for his daughter's death.
She was killed in the explosion that day.
I think everything he's done
has been to avenge her.
Ten years ago.
he broke into a military site
and was arrested for trespassing.
The site of the explosion.
On the same date.
And you think he might show tonight?
He just might.
You came alone to arrest him?
So you're not acting
under official orders. are you?
-What are you doing. Max?
-I'm guessing it's an undercover mission?
No. no. no. no. It's not a mission.
I'm not working undercover.
It's nothing at all. Just go home. Max.
If it's not a mission.
you can't tell me what to do.
That explosion killed that girl
and my dad.
And you. my dad's partner.
my godfather. my mentor.
you were there when it happened.
and you think I'll stay out of it?
Here.
What is this?
It's not registered?
Don't worry.
But we're just here
to arrest Mayard. right?
Of course.
It's a ten-minute walk
to the entrance of the facility.
Remember the riddles my dad used to tell?
Yeah.
How do you flush out a bad guy
who's holed up without hostages?
Come on. what do you do?
Just wait till he comes out.
You're unarmed. So is your partner.
You're held at gunpoint. what do you do?
-Max.
-Know that one?
Yeah. sure. I know it.
You give it your all.
-You die for your partner?
-Huh?
No. you don't die for your partner.
You have faith in your partner.
You put your life in his hands
just like he puts his life in yours.
You trust that when the time comes to act
he'll be ready to act too.
The enemy can't fight
on two fronts at once.
Your faith has to be absolute.
Yup.
Be totally sure that no matter what.
you'll be there for each other.
That's the way it was
for you and my dad. right?
It was a long time ago.
Breathe out as you hit the water.
Good. now breathe.
Mind your head. Head up. Good.
Breathe.
Slow measured kicks.
That's it. Keep breathing.
Focus on that.
Stay relaxed.
That's it. go on. Kick faster.
Come on. tuck your pelvis.
-Fill up your lungs.
-Major.
Go on. That's it.
-Major!
-I'm in the middle of something.
-Watch out. you're tensing.
-Commander Berger. Any idea where he's at?
-Dunno. He might be training. I suppose.
-Might be training where?
That's it. PJ. Good job.
Major. it's important. It's about Mayard.
Can you take over here?
He could be climbing. shooting.
jumping. boxing. munitions training.
We work around the clock.
Could be anywhere. I'm not his mother.
Isn't a section leader
supposed to train with his team?
Normally. yes.
but today isn't a regular day.
It's the anniversary
of his partner's death. so…
Does his thing. I give him lots of space.
That's how it is. okay?
If we're done here.
I have a section to run.
Okay. PJ. nap time's over!
Give me another length!
That's good. Fill up those lungs.
The entrance to the lab?
Yeah.
It's David. Leave a message.
INTERNAL USE ONLY
DIED IN THE LINE OF DUTY FEB 10. 2010
February 10th.
Shit. February 10th.
Get your team ready.
I think I know where to find Mayard.
And I think David Berger's
heading there now.
Is this where it happened?
Yeah.
Tell me what really happened here.
What do you mean?
Max. your father. Laurent. died here
and we all have to live with that.
That's what happened.
You can cut the shit.
I read the incident reports.
You were the only one with him inside.
Why did everyone
write a report except you?
Why didn't Christophe say anything?
Why no report from you
if there's nothing to hide?
Because I was totally lost.
I'd hit rock bottom. okay?
Laurent was my best friend.
Almost a brother.
We went to the police academy and
did every stage of the training together.
I was best man at his wedding.
I became godfather to his son.
I didn't write a report
because I wasn't able to function.
You get it?
I was in the parking lot
before the explosion.
I heard Christophe ask you if you
had told me the truth about my father.
What did he mean by that. David?
Clear.
Police! Stop right there!
I'll go left!
Max!
Open your mouth.
Ah.
In the vest?
Yeah.
Shit.
I can't picture my girl.
I don't see her in my mind.
This is the only place
where I can remember her face.
See her again. my baby.
Is it like that for you with your partner?
Huh?
-We tried our best to save her.
-No. you stopped me from saving her.
I could have done it.
Do you know what it's like
to lose your daughter?
-I could have taken more from you.
-You okay?
Yeah.
Your dad was a hero. you know that?
He did everything he could to save her.
He gave his life for her.
Shut up.
On your knees.
Cross your ankles.
Hands on your head.
Max. Watch him. okay?
That guy.
he's a coward.
Ever wonder why he got out of there
and your father stayed behind?
You know about
the blast-proof armored doors?
Shut up.
No one ever mentioned them. huh?
They were activated before the explosion.
From inside.
Only one person got out of there.
That guy.
Which leaves us with only one explanation.
He ran for it and shut the armored doors
to save his own ass.
When he locked my daughter
and your father inside.
he chose his own life over theirs.
Max!
Oh.
Give.
Okay.
Look at me. Max. Hey! Look at me.
I'm the one who shot him. okay?
Are we clear? I'm the one who shot him.
And I was alone.
You got it?
Is what he said true?
Is it your fault my dad died?
You need to wake up. Max.
The team's almost here
and this is not a sanctioned mission.
If they find out you were here
and that you shot him.
you can kiss your career goodbye.
I don't give a shit about my career!
I want to know what you did!
What the fuck did you do?
Stop being a fucking fool!
Grow the fuck up!
This is not the time to argue.
You're going to do exactly what I say.
Turn off your cell phone right now.
Walk back to your car.
And go home!
And don't say a word to anybody.
Is that clear?
Do it! Now. dammit!
Beat it!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org